Don't set him off.
John Wick is a action, thriller film directed by Chad Stahelski.
Ex-hitman John Wick comes out of retirement to track down
the gangsters that took everything from him.
John Wick, played by Keanu Reeves.
Viggo Tarasov, played by Michael Nyqvist.
Iosef Tarasov, played by Alfie Allen.
Marcus, played by Willem Dafoe.
Avi, played by Dean Winters.
Ms. Perkins, played by Adrianne Palicki.
John Wick is an American media franchise created by Derek Kolstad.
It centers on a neo-noir action thriller film series directed by Chad Stahelski
featuring the eponymous character portrayed by Keanu Reeves.
Wick is a legendary hitman who is reluctantly drawn back
into the criminal underworld after retiring.
The franchise began with the release of John Wick (2014), which was followed by three
sequels: Chapter 2 (2017), Chapter 3 – Parabellum (2019), and Chapter 4 (2023).
Various spin-offs expanded the franchise: the prequel comic book series John Wick: The Book of Rules (2017–2019),
the prequel television miniseries The Continental (2023), and the spinoff film Ballerina (2025).
The films have received critical acclaim, and have been considered
one of the greatest action film series of all time.
Some critics and publications consider the first film, as well as
Chapter 4, as two of the greatest action films ever made.
The films have earned a collective gross of more than $1 billion worldwide.
Stahelski, Basil Iwanyk, and Erica Lee serve in
oversight roles for the John Wick franchise.
87North Productions, Thunder Road Films, and Lionsgate produce the franchise.
The film explores themes of hitman, bratva (russian
mafia), gangster, secret organization, revenge.
The tone is intense.